<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd">
<topic id="drill-down_xml"><title>Drill down into your data</title><body>
  <section id="title-drill-down-into-your-data-last_updated-1222020-summary-drill-down-into-the-answers-thoughtspot-delivers-to-gain-deeper-insights-into-the-many-layers-of-your-data-sidebar-mydoc_sidebar-permalink-collectionpathhtml">
    <title>Drill down into your data</title>
    <p>
      When you drill down, you can see more information about the data
      within your search. You can drill down into a datapoint to get a
      finer grained view of that datapoint and the data behind it. Move
      easily from a general view of your information to a more specific
      representation of the data behind a datapoint at a click. For
      example, in a <i>revenue by
      department</i> search, you may notice that your
      <i>clothing</i> department has the
      highest revenue. You can drill down on
      <i>clothing</i> by
      <i>product name</i> to find out which
      products contribute to those high sales. There is no limit to how
      deep you can drill down.
    </p>
    <p>
      You can drill down in both tables and chart visualizations, on
      both [standalone Answers]({{ site.baseurl }}#answer-drilldown) and
      on [Answers within Pinboards]({{ site.baseurl
      }}#pinboard-drilldown). When you drill down on Answers within
      Pinboards, you can either drill down directly, or drill down
      [using the Answer Explorer view]({{ site.baseurl
      }}#explorer-drilldown). [Answer Explorer]({{ site.baseurl
      }}/end-user/pinboards/answer-explorer.html) provides a flexible,
      AI-guided exploration of an Answer within a Pinboard.
    </p>
    </section>
  <section id="drill-down-on-an-answer">
    <title>Drill down on an Answer</title>
    <ol>
      <li>
        <p>
          Right-click the chart object (such as a column on a bar chart,
          or a section of a pie chart) or data point of interest in your
          answer.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Select <i>Drill down</i>. This
          limits the data you are exploring to that particular data
          point or chart object. ![Drill down from a data point]({{
          site.baseurl }}/images/drilldown-table.png "Drill down
          from a data point in a table")
        </p>
        <fig id="fig_1580796169_1"><title>Drill down from a data point in a chart</title><image href="https://docs.thoughtspot.com/6.0/images/drilldown-chart.png" id="image_1580796169_1" scope="external"/></fig>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          A list of dimensions appears. You can only drill down on
          dimensions, not on measures. Click any of the options to gain
          deeper insight into your data.
        </p>
        <fig id="fig_1580796169_2"><title>Drill down dimensions</title><image href="https://docs.thoughtspot.com/6.0/images/drilldown-productfullname.png" id="image_1580796169_2" scope="external"/></fig>
        <p>
          For example, if you choose to drill down on
          <i>dairy</i> by <i>product full
          name</i>, the following chart appears, showing dairy
          sales by product:
        </p>
        <fig id="fig_1580796169_3"><title>Dairy sales by diet type</title><image href="https://docs.thoughtspot.com/6.0/images/drilldown-example.png" id="image_1580796169_3" scope="external"/></fig>
        <p>
          Use your internet browser's back button to go back one step at
          a time. {% include note.html content="Your browser's back
          button only goes back one step on unsaved Answers. If you are
          working with a saved Answer, clicking your browser's back
          button prompts you to save your unsaved changes, and does not
          take you back to the previous step in your Drill down."
          %}
        </p>
        <p>
          You can continue to drill down in the data until you run out
          of relevant dimensions.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ol>
    </section>
  <section id="drill-down-within-a-pinboard">
    <title>Drill down within a pinboard</title>
    <p>
      When you drill down on an Answer within a pinboard, it works
      similarly to drilling down on the Answer itself. You cannot go
      back one step at a time, but you can reset the Answer when you
      finish drilling down. To return to the original answer, click the
      blue reset icon ![]({{ site.baseurl
      }}/images/icon-drill-down-20px.png){: .inline} at the bottom right
      corner of the Answer.
    </p>
    <fig id="fig_1580796169_4"><title>Reset your Answer</title><image href="https://docs.thoughtspot.com/6.0/images/drilldown-pinboard.png" id="image_1580796169_4" scope="external"/></fig>
    </section>
  <section id="drill-down-with-answer-explorer">
    <title>Drill down with Answer Explorer</title>
    <p>
      You can also drill down using the [Answer Explorer]({{
      site.baseurl }}/end-user/pinboards/answer-explorer.html) feature.
      Answer Explorer provides AI-guided exploration of an answer within
      a pinboard. When you drill down normally, you cannot go back one
      step at a time to see an earlier version of your visualization.
      You have to delete filters from the search bar, or start your
      search again. If you drill down with Answer Explorer, you can use
      the <i>go back one step</i> feature.
    </p>
    <p>
      As you drill down on an answer using Answer Explorer, use the back
      arrow ![]({{ site.baseurl }}/images/icon-arrow-left-20px.png){:
      .inline} to go back one step at a time. Click the reset icon
      ![]({{ site.baseurl }}/images/icon-reset-20px.png){: .inline} to
      go back to the original answer.
    </p>
    <p>
      If you want to go back one step at a time while drilling down,
      [add your answer to a pinboard]({{ site.baseurl
      }}/end-user/pinboards/about-pinboards.html#add-an-answer-to-a-pinboard)
      so you can use Answer Explorer.
    </p>
  </section>
  <section id="save-and-share-your-new-answer">
    <title>Save and share your new answer</title>
    <p>
      When you find a valuable insight using Drill down, you may want to
      save that Answer instead of trying to recreate it in the
      <i>Search</i> bar later.
    </p>
    <ol spacing="compact">
      <li>
        <p>
          Click the ellipsis icon ![]({{ site.baseurl
          }}/images/icon-more-20px.png){: .inline}.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Select <i>copy and edit</i>.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          <i>Save</i> your new Answer and
          continue working with it.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Alternatively, select
          <i>Download</i> to download an
          image of your current visualization.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ol>
    <p>
      You can also [share the Answer]({{ site.baseurl
      }}/end-user/pinboards/share-answers.html) by clicking the sharing
      icon ![]({{ site.baseurl }}/images/icon-share copy-20px.png){:
      .inline}. Otherwise, the Answer returns to its original state when
      you exit the page.
    </p>
  </section>
  <section id="share-your-data">
    <title>Share your data</title>
    <p>
      If you own a pinboard or answer, you can drill down to the data
      beneath. Users you share a pinboard or answer with can also drill
      down provided they <i>also</i> have access to the
      data on which the board was based. If you do not have access to a
      pinboard or answer's underlying data source, you cannot drill
      down. See [overview of sharing]({{ site.baseurl
      }}/end-user/data-view/sharing-for-end-users.html) to share your
      answers, pinboards, or data.
    </p>
  </section>
</body>

</topic>
